(日向翔陽)あ
≪完璧なサブレシブ≫
That was a perfect receive.
Could he be...
≪この人もしかして
俺より小さい
な
You're shorter than me?
ああ
てめぇ今なんつたこらぁ
What the hell did you just say?!
ごごめんなさ
S-Sorry!
Um...
あの身長何センチですか
How tall are you?
１５９だ
159 cm!
≪ひゃ１５０センチ台
H-He's in the 150s!
うおお
ななんだよ
What's with you?
This is the first time I've looked down at
someone since I joined a high school team!
高校の部活に入て
初めて人を見下ろしました
泣いて喜ぶな
大して見下ろしてねぇだろ
Quit shedding tears of joy!
You're barely taller than me!
(田中)
あおおノヤさん
Oh, hey, Noya!
おお龍
ん
Hey, Ryuu!
Nishinoya!
(澤村･菅原)西谷
(西谷)ちわす
Hello!
Oh yeah, you haven't met him before.
(澤村)そういえば初めてだたな
２年の西谷だ
This is Nishinoya, a second-year.
(影山･日向)ちわす
おすお前ら１年か
Hello!
Yo! You guys are first-years, huh?
You there, the tall guy with the mean look who served earlier.
さきのサブのヤツ
そこのでかくて目つきの悪い方
お前どこ中だ
北川第一です
What junior high are you from?
Kitagawa First.
For real?
(西谷)マジか強豪じゃねぇか
どうりであのサブか
That's a powerhouse team!
No wonder you had a killer serve.
I had to play them back in junior high and lost 2-1!
俺中学んとき当たて
２対１で負けたぞ
They had a third-year with a killer serve back then too.
そんときも１個上にサブ
(２人)相変わらずうるさい
He's as loud as ever.
What... What junior high did you go to?
にし西谷さんは
どこの中学なんですか
Chidoriyama.
(西谷)千鳥山だ
あ強豪じゃないですか
That's a powerhouse in its own right!
Why'd you come to Karasuno?
なんで烏野にやぱり
Was it because you heard that Coach Ukai was coming out of retirement too?
烏養監督の復帰を聞いて
いや俺が烏野に来たのは
Nah.
The reason I came to Karasuno...
女子の制服が好みだたからだ
すごく
was because the girls' uniform was right down my alley.
はあ
え
Of course, the girls themselves didn't let me down either.
(西谷)もちろん女子自体も
期待を裏切らなかた
The biggest reason, though,
それになんつても
男子が学ランだからだ黒のな
was the boys' uniform. Guys have gotta wear black, yo.
俺中学がブレザで
学ランに憧れてたんだよ
I had to put up with blazers in junior high, so I always wanted to wear these.
茶とかグレじゃなく黒な
(田中)分かる
And not in brown or gray, either. It had to be black!
I hear ya!
烏野は黒学ランだし
女子も制服かわいいし
Karasuno had black uniforms, the girls' uniform was cute, and it was close to my place.
家からも近い迷わず決めたね
It was an easy decision to make.
Kiyoko!
潔子さん
あなたに会いに来ました
I crossed the seven seas to come see you!
(菅原)相変わらず嵐のようだな
As usual, the guy's like a hurricane.
More like a guerrilla downpour.
ゲリラ豪雨
(澤村)はははやかましいだろ
I bet you think he's rowdy.
でも
プレはびくりするくらい
But, you know, he has a shockingly
静か
calm game.
で旭さんは戻てますか
So, where's Asahi? Is he back yet?
(２人)あ
いや
Nah.
あの根性なし
That gutless wuss!
Cut that out, Noya!
こらノヤ先輩を
そんなふうに言うんじゃねぇ
Don't call your senior a wuss!
Shut up!
うるせぇ
根性なしは根性なしだ
A wuss is a wuss!
旭さんが戻んないなら
俺も戻んねぇ
If Asahi ain't coming back, then neither am I.
(田中)おいこらノヤ
Hey, wait!
Noya!
(西谷)≪俺の仕事は
ただひたすら繋ぐこと
My only job is to keep the rally going.
空はスパイカたちの領域で
俺はそこで戦えないけど
The skies are the spikers' domain.
It's not a place where I can fight,
≪繋げば繋いでさえいれば
but so long as I keep the rally going,
きとエスが決めてくれる≫
our ace will definitely score.
≪壁に跳ね返されたボルも
Even if your spike runs into a brick wall,
今度こそ繋いでみせるから
I'll dig it out for sure this time.
だからもう一回
So please...
もう一回
トスを呼んでくれエス≫
Please call for a set once again,
ace!
Episode Eight:
The One They Call "Ace"
≫ああの
H-Hey...
ん
ニシヤさんリベロですよね
Nishiya, you're a libero, right?
A defensive specialist.
守備専門の
｢ニシノヤ｣だ
The name's Nishinoya.
なんで俺がリベロだて思う
ちちぇからか
Why do you think I'm a libero?
Because I'm short?
えいえ
レシブがうまいから
N-No.
Because you're a good receiver.
リベロてレシブがうまいから
やれるポジションでしょ
And I know libero's a position for good receivers, dude.
あですよね
Uh, scratch that last part.
Wow, you know your stuff.
お前よく分かてんじゃねぇか
あとキｬプテンが西谷さんのこと
守護神て言てましたし
Also, the captain called you our guardian angel.
Gua—
守護それなんだそれ
Wh-What the hell?
Giving me a fancy title isn't gonna sway me!
そんな大げさな呼び方されたて
俺は別に
ほんとに言てた
うんうんうんうん
Did he really call me that?
Yeah.
That cool title isn't gonna change anything!
(西谷)そんなカコいい名前で
呼んだてなぁ
I won't give in so easily!
俺はそんな簡単にはなぁ
ちくしょう大地さんめ
Damn that Daichi!
俺まだレシブ下手くそで
I still suck at receiving, you see.
バレボルで
いちばん大事なとこなのに
Even though it's the most important part of volleyball.
ん
だから教えてくださいにし
So please teach me how, Nishi—
西谷先輩
Nishinoya, sir!
Sir!
ん
お前
Hey...
(西谷)練習のあとで
アイスおごてやる
I'll buy you ice cream after practice.
え
(西谷)なんつても俺は
After all,
先輩だからな
I'm your upperclassman!
あそれじゃあ
Does that mean...
でも部活に
戻るわけじゃないからな
No, that doesn't mean I'm rejoining the team.
I'm just gonna teach you, is all.
お前に教えてやるだけだからな
あざす
Thank you!
(３人)ほ
(西谷)だからよ要するによ
(縁下)ん
Look, basically...
You just have go like zoom, whoosh, and bam.
(西谷)サと行て
スとやてポン
Like so.
(日向･月島･山口)ん
(田中)ダメだ
This isn't working.
Nobody can understand what he's saying because he moves on pure instinct.
本能で動く系のヤツは
何言てんのかさぱり分からん
Really?
そうですか
俺なんとなく分かりましたけど
I kinda got it.
お前も同類だかんな
お前が説明すときも
Well, you're one of his kind.
Your explanations are all "bam" and "wham" too!
バとかグワとかでよ
周りはさぱり分かんねぇから
Nobody ever understands that crap.
え
(武田)リベロて確か
If I recall correctly, libero's a specialized position, right?
特殊なポジションだよね
はい
Right.
Libero
Libero:
(澤村)守備専門の選手です
a player who specializes in defense.
They're barred from making any
offensive plays like serving or spiking,
サブスパイクなどの攻撃は
禁じられていて
but they can replace any player in the back row to strengthen the defense.
後衛にいる選手と入れ代わて
常に守備を固めます
まさに烏野の守護神かぁ
カコいいね
So he literally is Karasuno's guardian angel.
How cool!
あいつが戻てきてくれると
本当頼もしいです
It'd be truly reassuring if he came back.
あの小さい体で
存在感がすごく大きい
He may be small in stature,
but his presence is overwhelming.
You're pretty big. How tall are you?
Oh, Tsukki's—
Shut up, Yamaguchi.
西谷がいると
安心感が違うんです
It gives us peace of mind.
Sorry about that.
(菅原)にしても西谷
全然なまてないなぁ
Man, Nishinoya hasn't lost his touch at all.
謹慎中も
特訓してたらしいすよ
Apparently he was training even while he was suspended.
ママさんチムに交じたりして
はは日向みたいだな
He played with volleyball moms and stuff.
Sounds like Hinata.
あの西谷先輩
ん
Um, Nishinoya.
Who's this Asahi you were talking about earlier?
さき言てた
旭さんて誰ですか
Don't bring his name up just like that, moron!
バカ不用意に
その名を出すな
烏野のエスだ一応な
Karasuno's ace. At least on paper.
Ace?
So we do have one.
≪ちゃんとエスがいるんだ≫
何ぽかんとしてんだよ
What's with the blank look?
I wanna be the ace!
俺エスになりたいんです
あ
エスその身長で
The ace? With your height?
I like you, dude!
いいなお前
へ
I hear ya! Being the ace has gotta be so cool, right?
だよなカコいいから
やりてぇんだよな
Sure, why not?
いいぞいいぞ
なれなれエスなれ
Do it! Become the ace!
You seem way more promising than our current one!
今のエスより断然
頼もしいじゃねぇかなははは
けどやぱ
憧れといえばエスかぁ
But man, everyone dreams of being the ace, huh?
はいエスカコいいです
Yeah, aces are cool!
Just the word "ace" has a cool ring to it.
(西谷)エスて響きが
もうカコいいもんな
"Setter" and "libero" sound so boring in comparison.
セタとかリベロは
パと見地味だもんな
あまあまあ
(西谷)けどよ
There, there.
But you know what really gets the crowd going wild during a match?
試合中会場が
いちばんワと盛り上がるのは
(西谷)
どんなすげぇスパイクより
Not an amazing spike, no.
スパレシブが
出たときだぜ
It's when they see an amazing receive.
高さ勝負のバレボルで
リベロはちちぇ選手が生き残る
In volleyball, a sport where height means everything,
libero may be one of the only positions where short players can thrive,
数少ない
ポジションなのかもしんねぇ
けど俺はこの身長だから
リベロやてるわけじゃねぇ
but I didn't become a libero because of my height.
たとえ身長が２メトルあたて
俺はリベロをやる
Even if I were two meters tall,
I'd still be a libero.
Because it doesn't matter if you can't spike or block.
(西谷)スパイクが打てなくても
ブロクができなくても
So long as you prevent the ball from touching the floor, you can't lose in volleyball.
ボルが床に落ちさえしなければ
バレボルは負けない
(西谷)そんで
それがいちばんできるのは
And the one best equipped for that role...
リベロだ
is the libero.
S-So cool!
カカコいい
(西谷)ババカ野郎
Don't just blurt that out, dumbass!
そんなはきり言うんじゃねぇよ
にゃろう
アイス２本食うか
ソダ味と梨味
Want two bars of ice cream? Soda- and pear-flavored!
おす
(西谷)でエス志望
Yessir!
So tell me, wannabe ace.
What's your specialty?
お前の特技は
え
レシブはへたくそだけどよ
なんかあんだろ
You suck at receiving, but there's
gotta be something you're good at.
あえとおとり
U-Uh...
Playing the decoy...
あ鳥
Say what? Playing coy?
お囮
P-Playing the decoy.
なんでそんな
自信なさげに言うんだ
Why do you sound so down on yourself?
｢エス｣とか
｢守護神｣とかと比べて
Because it sounds so lame in comparison to "ace" and "guardian angel."
なんか
パとしないていうか
Who cares how it sounds?
呼び方なんて関係ねぇだろ
でも
But...
If you can help a teammate score by playing the decoy,
(西谷)お前の囮のおかげで
誰かのスパイクが決まるなら
then your role is just as important.
お前のポジションだて
重要さは変わんねぇ
Right.
今の烏野には
最強の囮がいるんだよな
Karasuno has the greatest decoy now.
今まで決まらなかた
スパイクでも
With the Hinata-Kageyama duo in our ranks,
I'm sure we'll be able to land spikes
we wouldn't have scored from before.
日向と影山のコンビがいれば
きと決まるようになる
うん
武田先生の言てた化学変化で
Yeah.
I get the feeling we can change thanks to the chemistry Mr. Takeda was talking about.
俺たちは
きと変われる気がする
(澤村)
いい方に変わるといいけどな
I just hope we change for the better.
(菅原)はは弱気やめろよ
Don't be so pessimistic.
Foot of the Slope
(武田)しつこいかもしれませんが
お願いします
I know I might be annoying you, but please.
未経験者の僕では
情けないですが力不足なんです
As much as it hurts to admit,
I'm too inexperienced to lead the team.
あの子らの可能性は
すばらしい
These boys have amazing potential.
どうか彼らに
指導をお願いします
Please coach them...
烏養君
Ukai!
(繋心)しつこいなぁ先生
Damn, you're persistent.
That's all I'm good for.
はい
それだけが取り柄です
何回言われても
コチなんかやんねぇよ
No matter how many times you ask me, I'm not gonna take up coaching.
監督やてたのは
俺のじいさんであて
My gramps may've been a coach,
but I told you that I'm not cut out for it.
俺は人に教えるガラじゃねぇ
つてんだろ
(繋心)先生あんたが欲しいのは
技術指導者もだろうけど
Look, teach. While I'm sure you want a technical coach,
何より名将烏養の名前だな
I know that the Ukai name is what you're really after.
正直それもあります
Honestly, that's part of it.
烏養監督が退かれてから
だんだん他校とは疎遠になて
Once Coach Ukai left, we started
losing our contacts with other teams.
今年
穴埋めで入た僕なんかでは
As a makeshift advisor who only started this year, I can't even arrange any practice matches.
練習試合も
取り付けられないんです
And you think my name could turn things around, huh?
名将の名前があれば
そんな状況も変わるかもてか
お願いします烏養君
I beg of you, Ukai!
(繋心)断る
I refuse.
あんたが本気なのは分かた
I get that you're serious about this,
けど俺はクソめんどくさい
高校生のお守りなんかごめんだ
but I don't wanna babysit a bunch of annoying high schoolers.
また改めて来ます
うくぅ
I'll come again.
I just said I didn't wanna do it!
だからやんねぇつてんのに
(武田)
しつこくてすみませんでも
I apologize for being so persistent,
but I'm sure you'll understand why once you see those boys play.
あの子らの試合を
見てもらえたら
その理由も
分かてもらえると思うんです
おいほんとに何度来たて
俺は絶対に
It doesn't matter how many times you ask.
I'm still not gonna do it!
ああくそ
Damn it all!
熱ぃ
Ow!
All right.
Haikyuu !!
(東峰)
おうスガ話すの久しぶりだな
Hey, Suga.
It's been a while.
Please...
頼む戻てきてくれよ旭
Come back, Asahi.
西谷も謹慎が解けて
戻てくるんだ
Nishinoya's coming back too. His suspension's been lifted.
Oh, that's good.
そうかよかた
西谷が後ろにいてくれれば
心強いもんな
It must be reassuring to know he has your back.
お前だてそうだよ
The same goes for you!
We all feel more at ease when you're there, calling for sets!
お前がトスを呼ぶだけで
みんな心強く思てるよ
気持ちはうれしいけど
I appreciate the thought,
俺が戻てもまた
みんなの足を引張ちまう
but I'd just be holding you all down again if I came back.
(菅原)聞いてくれ悔しいけど
Listen to this.
As much as I hate to admit it,
we have an amazing first-year setter now.
１年に
すごいセタが入てきた
We've also got the greatest decoy!
それに最強の囮もいるんだ
もうお前にばかり
負担がかかたりしないんだ
You won't have to shoulder the burden alone anymore!
新しい戦力に加えて
西谷とお前が戻てくれば
With these new members, all that's left is for you and Nishinoya to come back,
烏野は
落ちた強豪なんかじゃなくなる
and Karasuno won't be the fallen powerhouse anymore!
Our team is about to undergo a radical transformation.
チムが変わりつつある今こそ
大黒柱のエスが必要
Now is the time we need our ace—
Azumane.
(生徒)東峰進路指導お前の番
It's your turn for career counseling.
悪いスガ
Sorry, Suga.
やぱお前行けよ
You should go, dude.
お前がエス見たいて
言いだしたんだろ
You're the one who wanted to see the ace.
だだて
３年の教室なんて怖くて
B-But a third-year classroom's too scary a place for me.
(菅原)待てよ旭
(２人)旭
Wait up, Asahi!
Asahi?
What?
何
あ
Huh? What are you two doing here?
(菅原)あれお前ら何してんの
あえと
Well, uh...
Faculty Office
(武田)はいはい
ありがとうございます
Right.
Yes!
Thank you so much!
Likewise.
いえこちらこそ
はい失礼します
Goodbye.
くぅよしよし
All right!
This is a huge opportunity!
大きなチャンスだきと
I'm sure...
Training Camp
Practice Match
きと何かが変わる
I'm sure things will change!
Class 3-3
(菅原)紹介するよ
この前入た日向と影山
Let me introduce you.
This is Hinata and Kageyama. They're new members.
(東峰)おお１年かぁ
(２人)ちわす
Oh? First-years, huh?
Hello!
Hey.
(東峰)おす
≪身長は月島の方が高い
He's shorter than Tsukishima,
How many joined this year?
Four.
but he's got this huge presence.
They may be a bit unique,
but they're all promising prospects.
≪けどなんつうかでかい
この人が烏野のエス
So this is Karasuno's ace.
そうかぁ
≪あ見た目より怖くない≫
That so?
He's not as scary as he looks.
(東峰)頑張れよ
え
Do your best.
一緒に頑張らないんですか
俺エスになりたいから
Aren't you gonna do your best with us?
I wanna be the ace someday,
so I'd love to see for myself how a real ace plays!
本物のエス生で見たいです
(生徒)東峰先生待てるてば
Azumane!
The counselor's waiting, dude.
(東峰)
悪い俺はエスじゃないよ
Sorry, but I'm no ace.
あのケガとかですか
Um, did he get injured or something?
(菅原)
いやそういうのじゃないんだ
Nah.
It's not like that.
あいつが
The problem here...
バレを嫌いになちゃたかも
しれないのが問題なんだ
is that he might've fallen out of love with volleyball.
But why? He's so tall! And people call him the ace!
えあんなにおきくて
エスて呼ばれてるのに
なんで
(菅原)旭は
Asahi was the tallest guy on our team, and he had the power to go with it.
烏野でいちばんでかかたし
パワもあて
苦しい場面でも
難しいボルでも決めてくれた
He'd come up big in clutch situations,
no matter how difficult a set was to put away.
That's why all of us recognized him as our ace and placed all our trust in him.
だからみんなあいつを
エスだと認めて信頼して
However...
潰されたんですか
あ
Did he get taken out?
(菅原)ある試合で旭のスパイクは
徹底的にブロクに止められてさ
There was a match in which the opposition blocked all of his spikes.
あいつ人一倍
責任を感じちゃう性格だから
It hit him hard because he tends to take all the blame upon himself.
うん
なんだよ
What?
Is that enough to make someone hate volleyball?
それで
嫌いになちゃうもんなのかなぁ
ほかにもいろいろあたんだろ
I'm sure there were other reasons.
いろいろて
知らねけど
Like what?
Don't ask me.
But we don't know for sure that he's come to hate the sport.
まだバレが嫌いになたとは
決まてない
Yeah!
(西谷)ロリングサンダ
Rolling...
Thunder!
あうんナイスレシブ
ただの回転レシブじゃねぇか
Uh, nice receive.
That was just a rolling receive, dude!
なんで叫んだんですか
(月島)ぷ何今の
Why'd he yell that out?
The hell was that?
Kageyama! Tsukishima! Yamaguchi!
影山月島山口
まとめて説教してやる
You're all getting a talking to!
Bend over—I mean, sit down!
そこに屈めいや座れ
俺の目線より下に来い
教えてﾛｰﾘﾝｸﾞｻﾝﾀﾞｰ教えて
Let me look down on you!
Teach me! Teach me how to do the Rolling Thunder!
Hard at work, I see.
お疲れさま
みんなちょと聞いて
Listen up, guys!
みんな今年もやるんだよね
We're holding it again this year, right?
The Golden Week training camp, I mean.
ゴルデンウィク合宿
≪合宿
Training camp?
(澤村)はい
まだまだ練習が足りないですから
Right. We still need a lot more practice.
(武田)それでね
ｺﾞｰﾙﾃﾞﾝｳｨｰｸ最終日なんだけど
Now, for the last day of Golden Week...
練習試合組めました
(一同)おお
I've arranged a practice match!
(田中)
すげぇ頼もしいな武ちゃん
Wow!
That's awesome, Take!
(菅原)相手はどこですか
Who are we playing?
A Tokyo school with lots of history: Nekoma High.
駒高校
Also known as...
確か通称
ネコ
猫
"Cat."
Cat?
(田中)俺らも
話だけはよく聞いててよ
We've heard a lot about them too.
前の監督同士がライバルで
よく遠征に行てたんだと
Apparently we played each other a lot because our coaches were rivals.
ほぉ
(菅原)そうそう
Oh?
That's right.
｢名勝負猫対烏
ゴミ捨て場の決戦｣つて
These famous derbies used to be called the
"Battle of the Garbage Dumpster: Cat vs Crow."
(月島)それ
ほんとに名勝負だたんですか
Are you sure these matches were famous derbies?
We haven't had a connection
with them for a while, though.
でもここしばらく
接点なかたのにどうして今
Why now?
うん詳しいことは
あとで話すけど
Well, I'll let you in on the details later.
音駒ていう
好敵手の存在を聞いて
But for now, I'll just say that once I heard about it,
I wanted to restart the heated rivalry no matter what.
どうしても
因縁の再戦をやりたかたんだ
駒高校となれば
Once he hears we're up against Nekoma High,
Foot of the Slope
きと彼も動くはず
he's sure to make a move.
(繋心)へくしょんうぅ
(澤村)よしせかくの練習試合
ムダにしないように
All right.
A practice match doesn't come along all that often. Let's not let it go to waste!
気合い入れんぞ
(一同)おす
Yeah!
東京かぁシティボイめ
Tokyo, eh?
I'm gonna destroy those damn city boys!
けちょんけちょんに
してやるんだぜ
"City boys"?
(月島)シティボイて
(田中)うるせぇ月島てめぇおら
Not another word out of you, Tsukishima!
Daichi.
大地さん
ん
すみません
俺練習試合出ません
Sorry, but I'm not gonna play in the practice match.
西谷
Nishinoya.
Hey, what do you think this Tokyo school's like?
(西谷)翔陽はいいヤツだし
ほかの１年も
Shouyou's a good kid,
Think they're strong?
and while all of the first-years seem like oddballs, they're all interesting in their own right.
くせ者ぞろいだけど
面白そうなヤツばかで
これからこのチムは
なんかこう
I think this team's, uh, headed in the right direction now.
いい感じに
やていくんだと思います
俺もここで練習したいけど
I want to train here as well.
But if I were to play too, and we won with this lineup,
俺も試合に出て
このチムで勝たら
I feel like it'd end up proving that we can do without Asahi.
旭さんいなくても勝てるて
証明になるみたいで嫌です
And I don't want that.
(西谷)
今まで一緒に戦てきたのに
Not after everything we've been through together.
I-I'm sorry for acting so selfish.
わわがまま言てすみません
分かた
Gotcha, but attend the training camp.
でも合宿には出てくれよ
えでも
Huh? But...
Noya! Do it again!
ノヤさんもう一回
ロリングサンダもう一回
Do the Rolling Thunder one more time!
(澤村)な
(西谷)んん
Okay?
(澤村)お疲れした
(部員たち)した
Dismissed!
Thank you!
ぷは
旭さんが戻てくれば
Think things would be easier for Sugawara and Nishinoya if Asahi came back?
菅原さんも西谷さんも
いろいろうまくいくのかな
知らね
旭さんのこと
Hell if I know.
Sugawara said Asahi tends to take all the blame,
人一倍責任を感じる性格だて
言てたけど
菅原さんもそんな感じしねぇ
but don't you think he himself is like that?
どちも
自分に責任感じてんだろ
I guess they both feel equally guilty.
一人で勝てるわけないのにな
Even though there's no way you can win by yourself.
おお前がそれ言う
Y-You're one to talk!
俺はお前の名言
鮮明に覚えてるぞ
I clearly remember what you said, you know.
"If I'm stuck working with him,
｢レシブもトスもスパイクも
全部俺一人で
やれればいいのにて思てます｣
I'd rather do every receive, spike, and set by myself."
うるせぇ
｢やれればいいのにて思てます｣
Shut up!
"I'd rather do everything by myself..."
うらぁ
Everyone on our side of the court
should be our ally, without exception.
ネトのこち側は
もれなく味方のはずなのに
ああ
こち側がぎすぎすしてんの
So I can't stand it when things on our side are all awkward.
やだな
気持ちはうれしいんだけど
I appreciate the thought...
なんで一緒に練習したこともない
俺が気になるの
But why are you so hung up over me? We've never even practiced together.
B-Because if you don't come back, our seniors will never cheer u—
あ旭さんが戻てこないと
２３年生が元気ないから
でけぇよ
Keep it down, dumbass.
(東峰)はは面白いなお前ら
You two are a riot.
But I'm sorry.
けど悪い
え
(東峰)俺はね
高いブロク目の前にして
I used to visualize breaking through high blocks in front of me,
それを打ち抜く
イメジみたいなのが
全然
見えなくなちゃたんだよ
but I've completely lost that ability now.
必ずシャトアウトされるか
I keep seeing images of getting shut out,
or getting so scared of it that I self-destruct.
それにビビて自滅する自分が
頭ん中をよぎるんだ
い１年のチビに
こんなこと言われたら
I'm just a first-year midget, so you
might think I'm cocky for saying this.
生意気て思うかもですけど
(東峰)思わないよ何
I won't. Go ahead.
それ分かります
I get what you're saying.
I have neither the height nor the technique, so I keep getting my shots blocked.
俺背が低くて技術もないから
ブロクに捕まてばかで
でも今は
こいつのトスがあるから
But now,
with this guy setting for me, I can evade
any block, no matter how high it may be.
どんな高いブロクでも
かわせます
ブロクが
目の前からいなくなて
The blockers vanish from my sight,
and I get a clear view of the other side of the net.
ネトの向こう側が
ばあと見えるんです
(東峰)
≪あその景色ちょと分かる≫
Yeah, I kinda know what that view is like.
そんでいちばん高いとこで
ボルが手に当たて
The ball hits my hand when I'm at the highest point on the court,
ボルの重さが
こう手にズシとくる感じ
and I can feel all of its weight in my palm.
大好きです
I love it!
(東峰)≪それもよく知てる≫
I also know that feeling well.
俺旭さん羨ましいです
今の俺には
I envy you, Asahi.
Right now, I have neither the height nor the power to break through blocks on my own.
一人でブロクをぶち抜く
タパもパワもないけど
旭さんにはそれがある
But you do.
今までたくさん
ブロｯクされたかもしれないけど
So what if you've had plenty of spikes blocked?
Haven't you scored with loads more?
それよりもといぱいのスパイク
決めてきたんですよね
That is why everyone calls you the ace.
だからみんな
旭さんをエスて呼ぶんだ
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]ｷｰﾝｺｰﾝｶｰﾝｺｰﾝ(ﾁｬｲﾑ)
時間だ戻るぞ
Time's up. Let's head back.
アホ遅刻する
あ
Move it, moron. We'll be late.
Um...
一人で勝てないの当たり前です
It's only natural that you can't win all by yourself.
コトには６人いるんだから
That's why you take the court in teams of six.
俺もそれ分かたの
ついこないだなんで
Though I didn't realize that until very recently either,
so I'm not exactly one to talk.
偉そうに言えないすけど
失礼します
If you'll excuse me.
(生徒)一緒に帰か
(生徒)おおなんか食てく
Let's go home, man.
Wanna grab a bite on the way?
≫キュキュキュキュ
もう一本もう一本来い
うるせぇ分かてんだよ行くぞ
One more!
Gimme one more!
Shut up! You don't need to tell me!
Here it comes!
おお
あ
Yeah!
((そんでいちばん高いとこで
ボルが手に当たて
The ball hits my hand when I'm at the highest point on the court,
ボルの重さが
こう手にズシとくる感じ
and I can feel all of its weight in my palm.
大好きです
I love it!
≪知てる≫
I know.
≪よく知てる≫
I know it all too well.
Next Episode Preview
I wish Azumane would hurry up and come back.
東峰さん早く戻てこねぇかな
不精ひげ生えてた
はあ
He had stubble.
What?
Maybe I could be more like an ace by growing some stubble!
俺も不精ひげ生やしたら
エスぽくなれるかも
Do hair growth products work on beards as well?
ひげも育毛剤で生えてくんのかな
知るかボケェ
Hell if I know, jackass!
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
Episode Nine:
A Set For the Ace
"A Set For the Ace."